《女子监狱》
第二季第一集
查普曼
Chapman!
查普曼  该出发了  起来  起来
Chapman, let's go. Up, up, up.
什么  我醒着呢
What? I'm up.
是站起来
On your feet.
我以为...
I thought...
今晚不是该弗利值班吗
I thought that Foley was on duty tonight.
已经到吃早餐的时间了吗
Is it breakfast already?
没有  但如果你饿了的话
No, but if you're hungry,
你可以从墙上把昨天的饭舔着吃了
you can lick yesterday's off the wall.
真恶心
Nasty.
不  这...
No, this...
这  这是艺术
this... this is art.
这是一只小黄莺在吸食水仙花的花蜜
This is a yellow warbler drinking out of a daffodil.
它就是喝不够
She just cannot get enough.
我打算称这幅画为《饥渴的小鸟》
I'm calling it Thirsty Bird.
已经快完工了
It's almost done.
这里闻着跟复活节的臭味一样
Smells like old Easter in here.
我讨厌煮熟的蛋黄
I hate cooked yolks.
你没办法完工了
Well, you won't be finishing...
怎么了  发生什么事了
Why? What's happening?
也别想再烦我了
... or annoying the living crap out of me.
给我站起来  囚犯
Stand up on your goddamn feet, inmate!
你要撒尿吗
Do you need to pee?
我要知道这是怎么回事
I need to know what's going on.
如果是要举行听证会  我有权到场参加
If there was a hearing, I was entitled to be there.
你是要带我  去重刑监狱吗
Are you taking... am I going to Max?
记好  我问过了
Remember, I asked.
那只小黄莺看着像是黄色的愤怒的小鸟
That warbler looks like the yellow Angry Bird.
求你了
Please...
是因为佩萨塔琪的事吗
is this about Pennsatucky?
求你了
Please.
她怎么样了
What happened to her?
我们是要去哪儿
Where are we going?
上货车
Into this van.
是要送我回惩教所吗
Am I going back to camp?
别再问我了  上去
Ask me more questions. Go ahead.
该死  你不能先把车内弄暖和一点吗
Shit, you couldn't warm this bitch up first?
没人事先通知我要押送这名犯人
Not a lot of warning on this one.
求你们告诉我这是要去哪儿
Please tell me where we're going.
我们是要回惩教所吗
Are we going back to camp?
说句是还是不是就行了
Just a yes or a no.
点头摇头也行
A head nod?
你新年时认识的那个
What's up with the
长得像米拉・库尼斯的妹子怎么样了
Mila Kunis chick from New Year's?
就是个神经病
Total psycho.
她昨天给我发短信说
She texted me yesterday,
"我们哪次能不能在晚上10点前见面"
"How about we meet before 10:00 P.M. sometime."
结尾是句号  不是问号
With a period, not a question mark.
搞毛啊
The fuck?
对我一副命令的口气
Ordering me around.
她虽然脸长得像库尼斯
And she's got that Kunis face,
但却没有库尼斯那样的翘臀
but she does not have that Kunis ass.
你得有库尼斯那样的翘臀
And you gotta have that Kunis ass
才有资格对别人呼来喝去  而不用礼貌地询问
if you're gonna be tellin', not asking.
你必须有那个翘臀才行
You got to have the ass.
怎么可能顺从于一个屁股扁平又要求甚多的娘们儿
Can't abide by demanding flat-ass poochies.
娘们儿
Poochies?
不能再说"母的"了
Can't say "Bitches" no more.
那很侮辱人
It's degrading.
9号货车  可以开走了
Van nine, you're cleared to go.
-转移出去  -转移出去  转移出去
- Processing out. - Processing out? Processing out?
从禁闭室转移出来吗
Processing out of the SHU?
你新刮的胡须看着不错嘛
I'm digging the fresh shave.
不是吗
No?
不是吗  那是要把我从哪儿转移出去
No. Then what am I processing out of?
到后面去
Come around back.
是要把我从哪儿转移出去
What am I processing out of?
祝你好运了  查普曼
Good luck with it, Chapman.
是要我上那辆车吗
Is that for me?
好吧  这玩意儿
Okay, these things...
-手铐勒得好紧  -没错
- These are really tight. - Yep.
我还是拥有基本人权的
I still have basic human rights.
你不能在大半夜把我推上一辆神秘巴士
You cannot put me on a mystery bus in the middle of the night
并且不告诉我目的地是哪儿
and not tell me where I'm going.
我要求知道我是要被送去哪儿
I demand to know where I am being taken!
我不可能顺从于一个要求甚多的娘们儿
Can't abide demanding poochies.
带着你那扁平的屁股滚上车去
Get your flat ass on the bus.
坐下
Take a seat.
囚犯
Inmate!
冷静点
Cool it.
他在看我们呢
He's looking!
-所以呢  -所以我们有麻烦了
- So? - So we'll get in trouble.
没人会有麻烦的  帕波
No one's getting in trouble, Piper.
去年  玛茜・克莱恩就摔坏了脚踝
Last year, Marcy Klein broke her ankle.
她后来不得不植入钢针什么的
She had to get pins in it or something.
那是因为她试图以哈基式跳跃动作跳下车
Yeah, 'cause she tried to do a herkie on her way out.
好啦  然后我们都会去莱恩家的
Come on, we're all going to Ryan's after.
快到了  你们准备好了吗
We're getting close. You guys ready?
他喷了古龙水  好恶心
Ew, he wears cologne. It's gross.
如果被我爸发现  我一定会被禁足的
If my dad finds out, I'm totally getting grounded.
如果他没发现的话
And if your dad doesn't find out,
或许我们就会被邀请参加莱恩家的除夕夜派对
maybe we'll be invited to Ryan's New Year's Eve party.
或许下个学期开学时
Maybe we won't go into next semester
我们就不会像现在这样不受欢迎了
being the same lame losers we are now.
我不需要通过跳下巴士来证明我很有趣
I don't have to jump off a bus to prove I'm fun.
我本来就很有趣
I'm fun.
我知道这一点  但是...
I know that. Just...
其他人都不知道这一点
no one else really does.
来吧
Come on.
开始吧
Here we go.
祝您圣诞节乐翻天  拉尔夫
Have a rad Christmas, Ralph!
跳吧
Go!
我理解妮可和波京不跳的原因
I understand Nicole and Bojing,
但你怎么也不跳呢
but why didn't you jump?
我已经把时速降到5英里了  这是个传统
I slowed to 5 miles an hour. It's tradition.
这是不必要的冒险
Unnecessary risk.
你是那种乖乖女啊
You're one of those.
我爸说我该有点个性
My dad says I should have strength of character,
而不是只会跟风
not be a lemming.
嘿  乖乖女  帮我把车门关上好吗
Hey, daddy's girl, get the door for me, will you?
你知道我们要被送去哪儿吗
Do you know where we're going?
可能是密西西比州
Hoping for Mississippi.
什么
What?
他们怎么能不告诉我们是要去哪儿呢
How can they not tell us where we're going?
真够操蛋的
This is so fucked!
安静
Hush it!
我真该尿一下的
Oh, I should've peed!
麻烦问一下
Excuse me.
能不能找个地方停一下让我上个厕所
Is there any way that we can stop for a bathroom?
我们是要下去了吗
Are we getting off?
你他妈怎么搞得好像我知道这车的行车安排一样
Why do you keep thinking I know what the bus schedule is?
我狗屁都不知道  跟你一样
I don't know shit... same as you.
都坐到后面去
All the way to the back!
我真的很尿急
It's just that I gotta pee so badly.
他们肯定得让我们撒尿的呀  对吧
They have to let us pee, right?
你觉得我该再申请一下吗  我该再...
You think I should ask again? Should I ask...
他们是不会让你撒尿的
They ain't gonna let you pee.
没人提醒你夹个小尿垫吗
No one told you to wear a pee pad?
-什么  -尿垫
- A what? - A pee pad.
把两张大号卫生间叠在一起  双重防护
Two maxis stacked so they like a maxi-maxi.
然后每次尿出一点点
And then you just let out a little at a time.
有些人会在下面垫两张
Now, some people do two down
再来一张从前面穿过  一张从后面穿出
and then one across the front, one across the back
像是尿布一样
like a diaper,
但是我呢  就垫两层就行了
but me, I just do a double stack.
没人告诉过我  我上个月一直被关禁闭着
Nobody told me. I've been in seg for the last month.
我这会儿就在尿呢
I'm doin' it right now.
下车吧  女士们  前面下车
Here we go, ladies. Exit to the front.
飞机
An airplane?
我们竟然要上飞机了吗
We're getting on a fucking airplane?
快走
Let's go.
把舌头伸出来
Stick out your tongue.
好了  下一个
All right. Next!
把舌头伸出来
Stick out your tongue.
抬上去
Up.
-抬上去  -我的舌系带比较紧
- Up! - I got a tight lingual frenulum.
我不需要知道这个
I really don't need to know about that.
伸出来  否则我就把它扯出来  快点
Stick it up or I'll rip it out. Come on.
老天啊
Oh, Christ.
那不是我的
That's not mine.
狗日的
Fucker.
-过来  -放开我
- Come on. - Let me go!
-把她的嘴罩起来  -放开我
- Get her covered. - Let me go!
帮我记上遭受袭击和职业性接触有害因素
Write up assault and occupational exposure, please.
下一个
Next!
你不喜欢吐人口水吧
You're not a spitter, are you?
不会的  长官
No, sir.
你没偷藏东西吧
Not hiding anything?
只有一个胀满的膀胱
Just a very, very full bladder.
把舌头伸出来
Stick out your tongue.
抬上去
Up.
好了  在飞机上提醒我一下  我给你找个厕所
All right. Remind me on the plane. I'll get you to a bathroom.
-谢谢你  -也谢谢你没尿在裤裆里
- Oh, thank you. - Thank you for not peeing your pants.
嘿  你能告诉我我们是要去哪儿吗
Hey, can you tell me where we're going?
不能  下一个
Nope. Next!
走吧  快点
Let's go. Today.
坐这儿
Here.
-那是什么动静  -那很正常
- What was that? - It's normal.
这是她第一次坐飞机
It's her first time on an airplane.
我不能说话  我尿急
I can't talk. I gotta pee.
走路和嚼口香糖同时进行有什么影响吗
Can't walk and chew gum at the same time?
随便吧
Whatever.
坐下  别乱动
Sit. Stay.
长官
Sir...
-洗手间在哪儿  -对哦
- the restroom? - Oh, right.
我去给你找个女法警来  坐着别动
Let me just get you a female Marshal here. Sit tight.
不  我已经坐了5小时了
No, see, I... I've been sitting tight for about five hours.
求你了  我不介意男警卫带我去上厕所
Please, I'm all good with a male guard.
我是法警  警卫是在海滩巡逻的那种
I'm a Marshal. Guards work at the beach.
求你别提任何跟水体有关的东西
Please don't mention anything that's near a body of water right now.
好吧  跟我来
All right, follow me.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
-门在... -没有门  开始吧
- Where's the... - No door. Let's go.
所有人都上来了  长官
Everyone's on, sir.
很好  告诉飞行员我们正在进行最后的安检
Great, tell the pilots we're running final security check.
你能不能  稍微尿快一点
Can you, uh... kind of hurry it up a bit?
我已经尽可能地快了
I'm going as fast as I can.
是吗  我听这声音有点不够力道啊
Really? 'Cause it sounds a little light.
好多了
Better.
电影中  飞机上总会出现氧气罩
In the movies, there's always this thing about oxygen masks.
突然从机舱顶部掉下来什么的
They come out of the ceiling or somethin'.
会有人来给我们演示怎么用吗
Is someone gonna tell us about those?
借过一下
Oh, excuse me.
真有礼貌
Polite.
天啊  铐得真紧
Damn. Tight.
你一定惹毛了给你戴手铐的人
You must've really pissed off whoever put these on.
我是个要求甚多的娘们儿
I was a demanding poochie.
你是会告诉我们目的地是哪儿
Do you tell us where we're going
还是等我们落地后要给我们戴上眼罩
or do you guys hand out blindfolds when we land?
还是个闹腾的
Oh, a frisky one.
我喜欢这样的
I like that.
系好安全带
Seat belts.
-安全  -安全
- All clear! - All clear.
天啊  天啊  它在动了
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, it's moving.
我们在动了
We're moving.
这玩意儿肯定重达千万磅
This thing must be, like, a bazillion pounds.
要怎么飞起来啊
How's it gonna fly?
我曾经读过一篇文章说  你吃飞机餐死亡的概率
You know, I read once that you have a better chance of dying
都比发生空难死亡的概率要高
from the food on an airplane than in an actual crash.
飞机上还提供食物吗
Do they serve food on this flight?
那不是会让飞机变得更重吗
Won't that make the plane heavier?
把遮光板拉上
Close the shade...
假装你是在坐地铁就好了
and pretend you're on the subway.
我表弟就是死于地铁事故
My cousin died in a subway crash.
好吧
Okay.
搞毛啊  她是睡着了吗
What the fuck? Is she asleep?
天  我希望是这样
Boy, I hope so.
你觉得我该叫人来帮忙吗
Do you think that I should get somebody?
不  不要  千万不要
No! No, hell, no.
她肯定因为压力过大才这样
It must be a stress thing.
当我焦虑不安时  眼睛会很怪异地抽动
When I get agitated, I get this really weird eye twitch.
尽管现在我并未表现出这种症状
Although it's not happening right now.
我觉得我现在已经过了压力阶段
I think I've moved beyond stress
陷入了更加令人烦扰不安的状态中
into something more deeply disturbing.
我带了凡士林
I got Vaseline.
我一个朋友  她也乘过这趟班机
A friend of mine, she took this flight,
她说旅途很漫长  空气很干燥
and she said it was so long and so dry
让她脸上的皮肤都要裂开了
that her whole face almost cracked open.
-你想来点吗  -不了  谢谢
- You want some? - No, thanks.
不  我这儿有一大坨  你待会儿想要可以拿
No, I got a whole glob if you want some later.
我不想要
I don't want any.
我来点吧  这里真是干燥得要死
I'll take some of that. It's dry as shit in here.
来  帮我一下
Come on, help me out.
给
Here.
即使我愿意触碰她的耳朵
Even if I was willing to touch her ear glob
即使我成功在手铐的束缚下
and even if I could reach across the aisle
把手伸到过道那边  且不被警卫们发现
with these shackles on and no guard noticing,
你凭什么认为我可以把手伸到
what makes you think that I could
你的面具下面  触碰到你的嘴唇
get up underneath that mask and touch your lips?
操你妈的  贱人
Fuck you then, bitch.
你都不愿意试试吗
You ain't even willin' to try?
抱歉
Sorry.
这家伙想问题真的挺透彻的  对吧
Well, this one really thinks shit through, don't she?
你个丑逼给我闭嘴
Shut your ugly face.
没人告诉过你皴裂是会要人命的吗
No one ever tell you crack kills?
让我怀念这家伙醒着的时候了
Makes me miss when this one was conscious.
我叫洛莉
Lolly.
-帕波  -你好
- Piper. - Hey.
求你告诉我你知道这架飞机的目的地是哪儿
Please tell me you know where this plane is going.
不知道
Nope.
但如果有暖气和床  那就比我之前待的地方好
But if it's got heat and a bed, it's better than where I been.
你做了什么恶事吗
You do something really bad?
反正不是什么好事
Well, it wasn't good.
我做了一些坏事  然后进了监狱
I did something kind of bad... and I was doing my time for it.
然后我又做了...
And then I did this, uh...
我又做出了一件事
I did this other thing.
我做出了一件非常非常恶劣的事
I did this really, really bad thing...
我觉得我就是因为这事被转送的
and I think maybe I'm going away for it...
要离开很长时间
for a long time.
你做了什么...你..
What... Did you...
你是杀了人吗
did you kill somebody?
我不知道
I don't know.
有个女孩...
I mean, this girl...
那个女孩  她追着我  不肯停下
this girl, she was coming after me and she was not gonna stop.
而且
And...
她
she...
简直是...
is...
或者说生前是
or was...
她生前简直
She was...
残忍无情
relentless.
我是说  跟疯了一样
I mean, just crazy.
太...
So...
so...
疯狂了
crazy.
然后我完全失去理智了
And I completely lost it.
我就...
I just, uh...
我的内心陷入了最邪恶黑暗的状态
I just went there...
我不知道...
and I didn't...
我之前都不知道  我内心有那么黑暗的地方
I didn't even really know that there was a there there.
但是
But, um...
我不知道
I don't know
那是最近才出现的  还是一直都在
if it just grew there recently or if it's always been there,
但是  那个心底最黑暗的地方
but that really... that dark place.
那个地方
That place...
让我不断地
that let me just keep on...
击打她
hitting her...
and hitting her...
然后...又...
and... and, uh...
击打她
hitting her.
我根本停不下来
I couldn't stop.
真够操蛋的  姐们儿
That's some shit, man.
各位乘客大家好  感谢你们搭乘我们的航班
Hello, passengers, we wanna thank you for flying with us today.
我们知道你们有很多航空公司可以选择
We know you have a choice in your air travel...
开玩笑的啦  你们根本没有选择
Kidding! You have no choice at all
因为你们是囚犯  我们看管的囚犯
'cause you're prisoners... our prisoners.
总之呢  请大家注意
Anyhoo, please note the
逃生门位于飞机的中部
exit rows located in the middle of the plane.
万一发生水上迫降的情况
In the case of a water landing,
我们强烈建议你们不要试图逃跑  重获自由
we strongly suggest you do not try and swim to freedom.
记住现在是冬天  体温过低是很危险的
Remember it's winter... and hypothermia hurts.
你们的坐垫可以用来做飘浮装备
Your seat cushion may be used as a floatation device.
请确保你们的安全带都已牢牢系好
Please make sure your seatbelts are securely fastened.
如果氧气罩掉落下来
If the oxygen masks come down,
请直接再推回到座位上方的隔板里就好
just push them back into the panel above your seat.
那些隔板有点问题
We're having some issues with those.
坐好  放轻松  享受一下舱内娱乐活动吧
Sit back, relax and enjoy our in-flight entertainment,
也就是   盯着漆黑的天空发呆而已
which is... staring off into space.
帕波  你能摘掉那傻逼的眼镜吗
Piper, will you please take off those stupid glasses?
好吧  别再叫我的真名了
Fine, but stop saying my name.
我现在是佐伊  叫我佐伊
I'm Zoe. Call me Zoe.
好吧  佐伊  他来了
Okay, Zoe. Here he comes.
给  两张《年少轻狂》的电影票
Here you go. Two tix to Dazed and Confused.
-祝你们玩得开心  -谢谢
- Have fun. - Thanks.
如果它被评为R级是因为含有极其不健康的内容
What if it's rated R because something really inappropriate happens,
那种会让我们一辈子留下心理阴影的东西
something that scars us for life?
你能住口吗  我们有票了  一切都好得很
Will you stop? We've got the tickets. It's all cool.
为什么不试着好好享受呢
Why not try to enjoy it?
天啊  是我爸爸
Oh, my God, my father!
好了行了  别再发神经了
Yeah, right. Quit being such a spaz.
不  我说真的  你看街对面
No, seriously, look across the street.
那是我爸
That's my dad!
-该死  -瞧见了吧
- Oh, shit. - See?
我日啊
Oh, shit.
那是谁啊
Who is that?
或许看电影会让你忘掉这件事
Maybe the movie will take your mind off it.
我多给了那家伙10块钱帮我们买票呢
I gave the guy 10 extra bucks to buy the tickets for us.
我操
Fuck my shit!
-我们到了吗  -天啊  我很抱歉
- Are we there? - Oh, jeez, I'm sorry.
我们至少是到了某个地方了
We're somewhere.
我睡了多久啊
How long was I asleep for?
我不知道  我把手表和自由都一起抛下了
I don't know. I left my watch back with my freedom.
好了听着  马上会有新的囚犯登机
All right, listen up. New inmates will be joining us.
记住了  不准有身体接触
Remember, there is no touching.
管好自己的手  脚
Keep your hands and your feet
腿  头发  脸
and your legs and your hair and your face
以及身体的其他部位
and all your other body parts to yourself.
如果你们无法遵守这一要求
If you cannot abide by this request,
我们会在落地后把你们关进禁闭室
we'll arrange for a nice little spot for you in seg upon your arrival.
如果不想惹麻烦的话  避免眼神接触就好
You wanna stay out of trouble, just avoid eye-contact.
安静点  各位
Settle down, people.
宝贝  我觉得你的姿色该坐头等舱
Oh, baby! I think you overshot first class.
杰
Jay?
不是吧  斯邦吉
No way! Spongie?
我操  妹子  你也被押上飞机了啊
Shit, girl, you got picked up?
是啊  都怪该死的罗比
Yeah, fuckin' Robbie.
-他在哪儿  -反正不在这儿
- Where he at? - Not here.
先生们  都在各自分配的位子上坐好
Gentlemen, sit your asses in your assigned seats.
我这儿有个位子留给你哦  美女
I got a seat for you, mommy.
都给你暖好了
Got it all warmed up for you.
你是个坏女孩  是吧
You a bad girl, huh?
你觉得那边的乡下人会狠干她的小骚洞吗
You think the suburbs over there can pop her puss like a sister?
黑人男一遇到白人女就瞎眼了
Black men get all snow blind.
完全不知道遇上我这种棕色女王
Don't know how good they got it
又牛逼又能干  会把你伺候得有多爽
with a cinnamon queen that knows how to handle her business.
我这儿也给你留了位置呢  宝贝
I got plenty for you too, boo.
是吧  头等舱美女
Ain't that right, First Class?
你愿意与人分享的
You can share.
我会让你愿意分享的
I can make you share.
眼睛看着前面  眼睛看着前面
Eyes front. Eyes front.
等等  等等  我来帮你
Hold up, hold up. Let me help you.
给
Here.
谢谢你  我饿死了
Oh, thank you. I'm starving.
每天都有食物吃还真觉得不习惯
It's gonna be so weird gettin' fed every day.
我一定会长胖的
I'm probably gonna get fat.
我看到山了  我们一定是来到中西部了
I see mountains! I think we're in the Midwest.
中西部是没有山的  蠢货
Ain't no mountains in the Midwest, dumbass.
只有平原和玉米
There's plains and corn...
以及一堆在投票时
and a shit ton of white people
完全不以自身最大利益为重的白人
who don't vote in their best interests.
不好意思  神偷卡门
Excuse me, Carmen Sandiego.
我都不知道这飞机上有个地理专家呢
Didn't realize we had a geography expert on board.
或许我们是要飞去维加斯呢  宝贝
Hell, maybe we're going to Vegas, baby.
各位法警  准备好降落
Marshals, prepare for landing.
芝加哥
Chicago?
听好了  所有人都转过身抱住脚踝
Now, everyone, turn around and grab your ankles.
我说了  转过身  抱住脚踝
I said, turn around and grab your ankles.
如果你们觉得害羞
If you're feeling shy,
我可以安排你们单独进行检查
I can set you up with a private show and tell...
是在禁闭室
in solitary.
屁股都翘起来吧  姑娘们
Let's get those moons rising, ladies.
列队
Line up!
女囚进来了
Females walking.
确保囚区安全
Secure the unit!
不准说话
No talking!
靠墙站好
Against the wall.
你  你  你  你  跟我走
You, you, you, you... let's go.
1278-1945号
1278-1945?
是我
That's me.
你的宿舍在楼上
You're up here.
A区  21号囚室  5号床铺
Unit A, cell 21, bunk five.
我能尽快跟我的律师见一面吗
Will I be able to speak with my counselor soon?
没人告诉我为什么被送到这里  以及要待多久
I haven't been told why I'm here or how long I'm staying.
我被加刑了吗
Have I been resentenced?
我只知道你住A区  21号囚室  5号床铺
All I know, unit A, cell 21, bunk five.
快别踩
Step off it!
别踩什么  天啊
Step off what... Oh, God!
没错  你现在是该祈求上帝的帮助
Yeah, you better be prayin' to God about now.
他   婴儿耶稣  佛祖  或者其他任何一个
Him, Baby Jesus, Buddha, whoever else
可以拯救你这走路不看路的蠢婊子的天神
might look out for dumbass bitches don't look before they stomp.
我就说让你今天各位当心吧
I told you to be overly cautious today.
我说让你慢一点  才能化险为夷
I said you've got to slow down in order to excel.
我警告过你不要搞这些巫毒算命的玩意儿了
I told you to quit it with that cosmic voodoo shit.
好吧  它死了
Yeah, he's dead.
她杀死了尤达
She killed Yoda.
对不起  尤达是你的宠物什么的吗
I'm so sorry. Was Yoda your pet or something?
它是我们的宝贝  傻逼
He was our prize, pendeja.
我很乐意帮你们另找一只宝贝
I would be more than happy to replace your prize.
你以为尤达是可以轻易被取代的吗
You think it's so simple to replace Yoda?
你欠我们的是一个冠军  贱人
You owe us a motherfucking master, bitch.
好吧  它在哪方面是冠军
Okay, what was he master of?
这些蠢娘们儿
These nuts...
她们会训练蟑螂偷运
they train cockroaches to run
香烟到禁闭室  明白吗
smokes back and forth to solitary, you know?
幸运的话  大多数蟑螂都有去无返
Most of 'em make it one way, if they're lucky,
但尤达每次都能逃回来
but Yoda always came back.
它这次可回不来了
He's not coming back this time.
你们在逗我玩呢吧
You guys are fucking with me.
尤达上周运送了200根香烟
Yoda brought in 200 stamps last week.
你要么给我们找个新尤达  要么一周运送400根
You owe us a new Yoda or 400 stamps a week.
你刚说是200根
You said two.
现在我们要求你在周末前运送400
Well, now we sayin' four... by week's end.
先给你打个招呼
And so you know,
萨莉讨债的方法可是相当惨无人道的
Celi's way of collecting debt has not been approved by the FCC.
身长最少要达到2英寸
It's gotta be at least two inches long...
最多不能超过4英寸
but no longer than four.
我会尽力的
I'll do my best.
那样才对嘛
That's right you will.
可怜的小尤达完全没料到会惨遭横祸
Poor little Jedi never saw it comin'.
现在有两张空床
We have two bunks available.
一张是乔伊丝的上铺  5号是在我上面
Uh, one over Joyce and five's over me.
你被分到哪个铺位
What are you assigned to?
5号  谢天谢地
Five... thankfully.
你是双子座吗
Gemini?
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
天生的感应能力
It's a thing.
你生日是什么时候
What's your birthday?
6月7号
June 7th.
年份呢
What year?
1981年
1981.
你的出生时间是什么时候
What time were you born?
我不太确定
Um, I'm not sure.
你妈从没跟你说过你出生时的故事吗
Your mom never told you your birth story?
我出生时是十月  暴风雪正肆虐
I was born in a huge snowstorm in October,
那对密歇根州来说很罕见
which is weird for Michigan.
马斯基根市
Muskegon.
我出生于早上4点  分毫不差
I was born at 4:00 in the morning... on the dot.
有教人怎么铺床的指导说明吗
Are there instructions for making the bed?
你以前从没铺过床吗
Have you never made a bed before?
抱歉  我不怎么看电视
Oh, I'm sorry, I don't... I don't watch a lot of TV.
你是名人什么的吗  还是说...
Are you famous or something? Or...
你是琳赛・罗韩
You're Lindsay Lohan.
不  我是说检查时是不是有什么标准
No, I mean for inspection.
我叫查普曼
I'm Chapman.
我叫马塞尔
Mazall.
我们整天都一起待在这里吗
So we spend all day in here together?
除了用餐时间
Except meals...
每天一小时休闲娱乐时间  每周出去到院子里一天
and one hour a day rec time and one day a week in the yard.
除此之外  就在这温馨的家了
Otherwise, home sweet home.
"家  温馨的家"
"Home sweet home."
晚餐时间到
That's dinner.
眼睛盯着地上盯仔细一点  姑娘
Keep them blue eyes on the floor, chica.
别想着找那些跑得快的
And don't even bother with the fast ones.
那些跑的慢的  训练出来的效果才最好
It's the slowbies that train the best.
她们是当真的吗
Are they for real?
她们对待蟑螂是相当认真的
They're pretty serious about their roaches.
在听到哔声后请留言
... so leave a message after the beep.
嘿  是我  帕波
Hey, it's me. It's Piper.
你叫帕波吗
Your name Piper?
是的
Yeah.
你认识斯奈兹吗
You know Snazz?
不认识
No.
斯奈兹以前跟我说过一个故事
Snazzy told me a story once
是关于一个叫帕波的女孩的  她们曾经一起跳过舞
about a girl she used to dance with named Piper.
她说她可以用阴道吹灭蜡烛
Said she could blow out candles with her coochie.
抱歉  我不是那个帕波
Sorry, different Piper.
好吧
All right.
莱瑞  我搞砸了
Larry, I fucked up.
我真的把一切都搞砸了
I really fucked everything up...
不是那种有趣的"真是典型的帕波作风"
and not in a fun-loving "Oh, that's so Piper" way...
我知道那已经很老套了
which I know was growing very old...
但是
but, um...
这事很严重
this is serious...
我...
and I'm...
我不知道是否还有机会挽救
I'm not sure it can be made right.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry...
我很抱歉再次
I'm sorry to have to pull
把你拖回到我混乱的生活中
you back into my Tilt-A-Whirl of a life...
但我需要你替我打个电话给你爸
but I need you to call your dad for me...
告诉他
and tell him that
我现在在芝加哥的大都市拘留中心
I'm in the Metropolitan Detention Center in Chicago.
告诉他我需要帮助
Tell him I need his help.
求你了  他得帮助我离开这里
Please, he's gotta help get me out of here.
你们是负责供餐的
You guys will be feeders.
把餐车推进来  分发餐盘  再把餐车推出去
Push the cart in, distribute the trays, push the cart out.
就是这样
That's it.
剩下的清洁工会做的
Cleaners'll do the rest.
好了  继续往前走
All right, let's keep walking.
*有了你  我的思绪才能安宁*
*You're the key to my peace of mind?*
*因为你让我觉得*
*Cause you make me feel*
*你让我觉得*
*You make me feel*
*像是自然的一个女人  女人*
*Like a natural woman, woman*
嘿  白人女  搜寻蟑螂进行得怎么样了
Hey, white girl, how the search comin'?
还没找到比较有能力的  但我依然信心十足
There are no real contenders yet, but I remain hopeful.
我来  告诉你一些事吧
Let me... tell you somethin'.
联邦警察把我关在这里5个月等着庭审
Fucking Feds locked me up here five months now waitin' for trial.
我丢了工作  车
I lost my job, my car.
我恨不得收集每一分钱  来养活孩子们
I'm scraping pennies together to keep my kids in the apartment.
你知道那些钱是从哪儿来的吗
You know where them pennies come from?
尤达  小精灵  弗莱德-萨维奇三世
Yodas... gremlins... Fred Savage IIIs.
萨莉辛辛苦苦地搞烟
Now Celi over here workin' hard to get smokie up to speed,
但是进展并不顺利
but it ain't goin' so well.
所以你能不能别再只说什么有信心
So how about, instead of you "Remaining hopeful,"
而是坐在门边守着
you go sit in front of that door
见到有蟑螂就给抓住
and start grabbin' what comes under it?
我要直接用手抓吗
I'm just supposed to grab it with my hands?
然后呢
And then what?
给我们  我是认真的
Deliver. I mean it.
趴在地上  把自己当做一块巨大的金色面包屑
Get on that floor, make like you one giant, blonde crumb,
立刻给我抓住一只好蟑螂
and grab yourself a fine carachacha now.
真是个乖姑娘
That a girl.
你能打个电话给你妈妈吗
Can you call your mom?
我真的需要知道你的出生时间
I really need to know your time of birth.
那可以帮助我弄清楚
It'll help me figure out
你的吸引力有多强
how strong your powers of attraction are.
那主要是指性伴侣间的
That's mostly for sexual partners...
不是指吸引昆虫的能力
not insects.
妈
Mom?
来帮我一下吧
A hand would be nice.
妈  我有事要告诉你
Mom, I have to tell you something.
什么
What?
老天啊
Oh, good heavens.
尼尔家终于决定给房子重新刷漆了
The Neals finally decide to repaint
却选择了那么丑的颜色
and they choose that color?
我一定要打电话给芭芭拉说一下
I've gotta call Barbara.
等等  妈
Wait, Mom?
怎么了
What?
我真的想把我看到的事告诉你
I really wanna talk to you about something I saw.
比尼尔家那绿色呕吐物般的屋子更糟糕吗
Was it worse than the Neals' puke-green house?
是的
Yes.
那说明肯定是重大消息
Well, that's saying something.
是什么事  宝贝
What is it, dear?
几天前
Well, the other day,
莎拉和我去萨福克看电影
Sara and I went to the movies at the Suffolk.
-莎拉・B还是莎拉・H  -莎拉・H
- Sara B. Or Sara H.? - Sara H.
继续说
Go on.
我看见了爸爸
I... I saw Daddy.
好吧
Okay.
他跟一个人在一起
He was with someone.
一个女人
A lady someone.
他吻了她
He kissed her.
你和莎拉・H去萨福克看了什么电影
What movie did you and Sara H. see at the Suffolk?
《年少轻狂》  但是...
Um, Dazed and Confused, but...
帕波・伊丽莎白・查普曼  你被禁足了
Piper Elizabeth Chapman, you're grounded.
什么
What?
那可是R级电影  你还没到17岁
That is an R-rated movie and you are not 17,
我也没有允许你去看那部电影
and I did not give you permission to see that movie.
你是怎么弄到票的
How do you even get tickets?
我不希望你再跟莎拉・H一起玩了
You know, I don't want you hanging around with that Sara H.
她把你带坏了
She is a bad influence.
在我打电话给芭芭拉时  把杂货都收起来放好
Please put away the groceries while I call Barbara.
那个颜色简直让我恶心想吐
You know, that color is actually making me feel nauseous.
我感觉要吐了
I feel queasy.
披上大衣  戴上帽子  除非你不怕冷
Grab a coat and a hat... if you dare.
你还真不怕冷吗
You're feelin' lucky.
你是在找宠物吗
You lookin' for a pet there?
不  说来话长
No, it's a, uh... it's a long story.
过来跟我们一起取暖吧
Come keep warm with us.
我们像企鹅一样  每5分钟转个圈
We rotate every five minutes like penguins.
你还有别的地方可去吗
Got someplace else to be?
没有
No.
蒂娜  波蒂  伊莲・托马克
Tina, Birdie, Elaine Toromocho.
-查普曼  -你们好
- Chapman. - Hello.
你来站在中间吧
Have a turn in the middle.
企鹅的父亲可真够爷们儿的
Fuckin' penguin daddies are fuckin' men.
想想刚刚当上父亲的雄企鹅待在一个地方
Imagine our baby-daddies staying in one spot,
没有食物
no food,
在彻骨的寒冷中  独自照顾企鹅宝宝长达几个月
taking care of the kids for months all alone in the freezing cold.
不可能吧
No way.
其实
You know...
帝企鹅天生就可以承受那样的环境
emperor penguins are set up for that...
从生理学角度上看是这样
physiologically speaking.
它们的羽毛很短  下面还有一层绒毛
They have short feathers and an underlayer of woolly down.
我曾经写过一篇关于企鹅的报告
I did a report on penguins once.
不过确实  真够爷们儿的
But yeah, fuckin' men.
帕波
Piper!
你还好吗
How you holding up?
你的声音让我很不爽
Your voice annoys me.
走远点
Keep walking.
干你丫的  我跟我朋友打声招呼
Fuck you. I'm saying hi to my friend.
她是你朋友吗
She's your friend?
我们是在...
We met on the, uh...
行了  回答我是还是不是就行了
Yeah, I asked you a yes-or-no question.
嘿  我要是你  就不要惹她
Hey, I wouldn't start shit with her if I was you.
她被送到这里  是因为她徒手杀了一个狱友
She's here 'cause she killed another inmate with her bare hands.
本来就是啊
You did.
你以前也沦落过其他监狱啊  小公主
So you've been down before, princess?
利奇菲尔德监狱
Litchfield.
敲死她的吗
Knuckled her?
你感觉到她骨头碎裂的声音了吗
Did you get to feel the bones crack?
是的  感觉到了
Yes, actually.
帕波  你被关在哪个区啊
So, Piper, what unit you in?
天啊
Christ...
你得收起你那诱人犯罪的嗲声音
you have to take that molest-me-daddy voice
立刻给我走远点
and go someplace else right now.
干你丫的  老女人
Fuck you, Menopause.
干你丫的  无名女
Fuck you, G.I. Jane Doe!
我们是要干一架吗
Oh, that's what we gonna do now?
我们就来好好玩玩吧
Oh, we are gonna play.
滚远点  你个臭狗屎
Fuck off, you piece of shit!
你想跟我干一架吗
You want to get in on me?
趴下  趴下你个贱人  干你丫的
Get down! Get down, you bitch! Fuck you!
帕波
Piper!
所有囚犯都靠墙站好  动作快点
Inmates, up against the wall! Let's go!
帕波  快帮我
Piper, help me.
所有人都站好队
Everybody, line up!
放风时间结束
Outdoor time is over.
快点  快点  都回各自的牢房里去
Let's go. Let's go. Back to your cells.
-靠墙站着  -艾丽克斯
- Get up against the wall. - Alex.
所有人都动起来
Everyone, move.
-艾丽克斯  -立刻靠墙站好
- Alex! - Up against the wall now!
转过身去  快点  好戏结束了
Turn around. Come on, show's over.
艾丽克斯
Alex!
都给我靠墙站着  别想捣乱
Move up against the wall. Don't you mess around here.
你的星宿图是水星三合火星
You have a Mercury trine Mars,
那会产生一种非常强大的力量
which is a really compelling dynamic.
我会再研究下你的星象  待会儿再来找你
I'm gonna work your chart and get back to you, okay?
蟑螂通常都是在地面才能找到的
Roaches are usually found on the ground.
我在院子里看到一个熟人  我得找到她
I saw someone I know in the yard. I need to find her.
她或许被关在别的囚区
She might be in another unit.
我们和B区C区的人一起放风
You know, we... we go out with B and C,
但只和A区的人一起就餐
but we only eat with A.
但我们要等一周后才会去院子里放风
But we won't be out in the yard for another week.
有没有可能在另外的时间见到其他区的人
Do we see any other units at any other times?
我们的休闲娱乐时间一致
We have the same rec time,
但是有门相隔
but the gate pretty much keeps us separate.
对了  你问到你的出生信息了吗
Hey, did you get a chance to get your birth information?
因为水星很快就要逆行了
'Cause Mercury's gonna be in retrograde soon
你不会希望遇到尴尬不顺的情况的
and you really don't wanna get caught with your pants down.
能把这个给我吗
Can I have this?
那个   我需要纸笔
That's... I need that...
你好啊  头等舱美女
Hey there, First Class.
我要你帮我个忙
I need a favor.
他们还说只有胖子会多要一份饭呢
They said the fatties would be the ones askin' for an extra tray.
不是  我需要传个纸条给别人
No, I need to get a note to somebody
但我不确定她被关在哪个区
and I'm not sure what unit she's in.
我觉得  或许你可以帮我传给她
I thought maybe you could, um, pass this to her?
她长什么样
What does she look like?
1.75米  黑长发  戴黑框眼镜
5'9", long black hair... secretary glasses.
她名叫艾丽克斯・沃斯
Her name is Alex Vause.
你愿意付出什么代价
What are you willing to give?
吻一下吗
A kiss?
这事很重要
This is important.
我能感觉的到
I can feel that.
好吧  帮你打个飞机吗
Okay, with my hand?
我是个捕食者  贱人
I'm a predator, bitch.
你主动献身就没意思了
Ain't no fun if you offer.
但在这种地方你根本
Well, there's nowhere for
没机会对我实施暴力侵犯
you to violently assault me in private here.
你到底想要什么
So what do you want?
你的内裤
Your panties.
他们还没发过新的
They haven't given us new ones yet.
我身上这条已经穿了4天了
I've been wearing these for four days.
那就更好了
Even better.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
艾丽克斯・沃斯
Alex Vause.
对于一个面临最后期限的女孩来说
For a girl with a deadline,
你还真有时间跑去跟那个枪手交朋友
you sure got a lot of time for socializing with the gun over there.
-这可不是个游戏  -枪
- This ain't a game. - Gun?
我朋友跟他在外面是认识的  他是个职业杀手
My girl know him from the outside. He kill people for money.
他是个杀手吗
He's a hitman?
我还以为他是个强奸犯呢  真是松了一口气
Oh, I thought he was a rapist. I'm so relieved.
你他妈真古怪
You fuckin' weird.
你得告诉我你是什么时候出生的
I need you to tell me what time you were born.
-我不知道  -快告诉我
- I don't know. - Tell me!
11:42
11:42.
-上午还是晚上  -上午
- A.M. Or P.M.? - A.M.
地点
Where?
康涅狄格州
Connecticut.
谢谢
Thank you.
其实  你进监狱了还挺令人惊讶的
You know, it's surprising you're in prison.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
通常来说  入狱的人
Typically, people in prison
都是被一股强大的力量牵引进了迷途
have been led astray by a powerful force.
但你的星象中并非如此
That's not in your chart.
会遇到熊和水  但不会进监狱
Bears and water, but not prison.
你确定你给我的信息都是正确的吗
You're sure you gave me all the right information?
很确定
Positive.
好吧  那我再检查一下
All right. Well, I gotta re-examine this then
因为你的第一宫和第十二宫绝对有点问题
because there's definitely some shit in your first and 12th houses.
在你的成长发育期发生过一些偏移
Something askew in your formative years.
你是被一股强大的力量引入迷途的吗
Were you led astray by a powerful force?
我把我女友的舌头咬下来吞掉了
I bit my girlfriend's tongue off and swallowed it.
那是我人生跌落之路的开始
Well, that was the beginning of the fall.
完全是盛怒难抑造成的
Pretty straightforward manic rage stuff.
倒也说得通  白羊宫上升
Makes sense. Aries rising.
抱歉  我不是想没礼貌  但我有事得先走了
Excuse me. I don't mean to be rude but I gotta go.
我喜欢你这股劲
I'm liking that hustle!
艾丽克斯
Alex.
艾丽克斯  你到这儿来干什么
Alex, what are you doing here?
你当时也在场吗  你看到我们了吗
Were you there? Did you see us?
她死了
She's dead.
我杀死了她  对不对
I killed her, didn't I?
-她死了  -你在说些什么呢
- She's dead. - What're you talk...
-杀了谁  你在说些什么呢  -佩萨塔琪
- Killed who? What are you talking about? - Pennsatucky.
什么  佩萨塔琪根本没死啊
What? Pennsatucky's not dead.
你确实把她打得够狠的
You fucked her up pretty good...
但那个臭婊子还活得好好的呢
but that piece of shit is very much alive.
你确定吗
You know that for sure?
我在洗衣房工作
I work in the laundry.
每天都有关于塔琪的病情恢复报告
Everyday there's a fucking progress report on Tucky.
小帕  你这人有很多特征
Pipes, you are many things,
但绝对没有杀人狂这一项
murderess is not one of them.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我没有杀死她吗
I didn't kill her?
没有  恭喜了
Nope, congratulations.
那你被关到这儿来干什么
So, what are you doing here?
那我被关在这儿干什么
What am I doing here?
为了庭审啊  傻瓜
For the trial, dumbass.
庭审  什么庭审啊
Trial? What fucking trial?
库巴的案子  他被引渡了
Kubra's. He's been extradited.
那意味着这一切都只是暂时的吗
So that means that all of this is only temporary?
天啊
Oh, my God!
天啊  我真是松了一口气
Oh, my God, I'm so relieved.
我就知道是这样
I mean, I knew.
我知道我被关禁闭时想得太多有点发疯了
I knew I went a little crazy while I was in the SHU,
但是  被押送到这里来
but, man, coming in here
一无所知  却以为...
and not knowing but thinking...
我真的处于崩溃的边缘了
I was really on the brink.
你恨我的
You hate me.
突然处于这种境况中  我都忘了你恨我了
In all of this shit, I forgot that you hate me.
但你还在跟我说话
But you're talking to me.
这意味着你不再恨我了吗
So does this mean you don't hate me anymore?
那意味着我今天暂时放下怨恨了
It means that I'm not holding grudges today.
见到你我很高兴
I'm happy to see you.
不准触摸
No touching!
艾丽克斯  快抓住那个
Ooh, Alex, get that!
-什么  -快抓住那个虫子
- What? - Get that bug!
它爬得很慢  而且个头很大
Oh, it's a slow one and it's a big one.
艾丽克斯  它是只体型庞大的慢蟑螂
Alex, it's a biggie slow!
快点啊  它或许会成为尤达的
Come on, it might be Yoda!
老天啊
Jesus Christ!
关禁闭把你脑子搞出毛病来了吧
The SHU really did do a number on you.
好吧  我欠我室友的
All right. I owe my bunkie,
她一天拉4次屎  没错  4次  当着大家面就拉
who takes four shits a day, yes, four, out in the open,
我欠她一只能运送香烟的蟑螂
I owe her a cigarette-toting roach
否则她会在我脸上纹身的
or she's gonna sic tattoo face on me.
庭审是什么时候
When is the trial?
就现在吧  他们随时都可能叫我们
Now, I guess. They can call us in any minute.
听着
Listen...
我们不能说我们认识库巴
we cannot say that we knew Kubra.
什么
What?
报复简直是他商业模式的一部分  明白吗
Revenge is part of his business model, okay?
变态的疯狂报复  记得与他撇清关系
Sick, deep revenge. Disassociate.
你从不认识他  你从没见过他
You never knew him. You never fucking met him.
那意味着在宣誓下撒谎
That means lying under oath.
天啊  真的很难跟上你的是否黑白观
Jesus, it is so hard to keep up with what's black and white with you.
库巴绝不会因为这事被消灭的
Kubra is never going down for this.
根本没有正义可言  帕波
There is no justice, Piper.
你到现在还不明白这一点吗
Don't you know that by now?
我们要为了自保而撒谎
So we will lie to protect ourselves...
反正我会的
or I will...
我希望你也这样做
and I hope you do, too.
你知道我爸出轨了吗
Did you know my dad cheats on my mom?
不知道  你是怎么知道的
No, how'd you know that?
我看到他吻别的女人  然后他们一起上了车
I saw him kiss another woman and then they got in a car together.
真的  他是个伪君子
Yeah, he's pretty much a big hypocrite.
很高端的词汇啊
Oh, big word.
才刚学到的
Just learned it.
然后我告诉了我妈  她竟然生我的气了
And then I told my mom and she got mad at me!
我被禁足了
I got grounded.
如果你仔细想想的话
Well, now, if you really think about it,
你能想象出你妈妈做出其他反应吗
could you imagine your mom having any other reaction?
不  不能
No, not really.
你是在说我应该闭嘴吗
Are you saying I should've shut up?
他出轨了  那是不对的
He's a cheater. That's wrong!
有时候不是对与错的问题
Sometimes it's not a matter of right and wrong.
而是你做出的选择要...
It's about making a choice that will...
对其他人造成的伤痛最小
cause the least amount of pain to others,
有些事放在心里就好
keeping things to yourself,
隐藏一些信息和感觉
sitting on information and feelings
带着秘密活着
and living with your secrets.
听上去好可怕
That sounds horrible.
没错  宝贝
Oh, it is, dear.
-奶奶  -怎么了  卡尔
- Um, Grandma? - Yes, Cal?
我刚刚试图把一根香烟射向外太空
I was trying to launch Whiskers up into outer space
现在我的房间似乎着火了
and now my room is kind of on fire.
上等咖啡算是我第二想念的东西
Decent coffee runs a close second to what I miss most.
莱瑞
Larry.
莱瑞才是我最想念的
Larry is what I miss most.
莱瑞是"人"  不是"东西"
Larry's a "Who," Not a "What."
听着  帕波  我是以你律师的身份过来的
Look, Piper, I've come here as your lawyer
我觉得我们最好主要谈谈案子的事
and I think it's best if we just stick to the case.
光明节过得怎么样
How was Hanukkah?
琼妮阿姨还跟那个话特多的男人在一起吗
Is Aunt Joanie still with the talker?
整整45分钟的时间里
Forty-five minutes
我听他说乳牛场的奶牛病了
I heard about diseased cows on dairy farms,
基因工程的可怕之处
the horrors of genetic engineering
以及对牛使用过多的抗生素等各类事情
and the overuse of antibiotics in cattle.
学到的就是  他只喝黑咖啡
Lesson being, he takes his coffee black.
好了  谈谈库巴・巴里克吧
All right, Kubra Balik...
你们贩毒集团中的大佬
the big jewel in your drug ring...
从欧洲被引渡回来接受庭审
was extradited from Europe to stand trial.
检诉方需要确定他的时间线
Prosecution needs to nail down his timeline,
他们正在寻找能够在这方面帮上忙的证人
they're looking for testimony that helps do that.
你有见过库巴・巴里克吗
Did you ever meet Kubra Balik?
当时比较混乱
It was a confusing time.
我想也是  但我的问题很清楚明白
I... I'm sure, but my question is pretty straightforward.
你见过库巴・巴里克吗
Did you ever meet Kubra Balik?
是的
Yeah.
是的  我认识他
Yes, I knew him.
以何种身份
In what capacity?
你知道他在整个贩毒集团中的角色吗
Were you aware of his role in the ring?
你听过他给别人下命令吗
Did you hear him give orders?
像这些问题
These are the questions
检方肯定会在你出庭作证前全部抛出来问你的
the prosecution's gonna be drilling you on before you testify.
好吧  但如果我作证  谁来保护我的安全
Yes, but what about my safety if I testify?
这家伙可是个狠角色
This guy is the real deal.
就我从《黑道家族》中看到的剧情而言
And from what I've seen on The Sopranos,
像这种人对于叛徒
these types do not take too kindly
是绝不会心慈手软的
to those that they consider traitors.
他们会雇佣迷恋内裤的杀手来解决掉叛徒
They hire killers with underwear fetishes to take them out.
他们追查这个案子已经5年了
They've been working on this case for five years,
花去了成千上万美元的经费
spent hundreds of thousands of dollars.
我觉得你至少可以证明
And I'm sure you, for one,
联邦警察有多么不爱花钱
can attest to how little the Feds like to spend money.
巴里克先生是个十恶不赦的坏人
Mr. Balik is a very bad man
他会被关在大牢里很久很久的
who's going away for a long, long time.
撒谎不是个办法
Lying is not an option.
你永远都会说真话吗
Do you always tell the truth?
有时候当别人问我
Sometimes when they ask
是否愿意为心脏病研究捐献一美元钱时
if I wanna donate a dollar for heart disease,
我会说我已经捐过了
I'll say I already gave,
但大多数时候  我都会说真话
but mostly, yes, I tell the truth.
说真话在我家是不被提倡的
Telling the truth wasn't much of a priority in my family.
只要大家在拍圣诞节家庭合照时笑得灿烂
You know, as long as everybody smiled pretty for the Christmas picture,
就尽情撒谎吧
lie it up.
我建议你不要在这事上延续你的家庭传统
I wouldn't carry on your family tradition here.
此事关乎犯罪  惩罚和正义
This is about crime and punishment and justice.
你得说出真相
You need to tell the truth.
是的  当然了
Yes, of course.
很好
Good.
我们去见见那些检察官吧
Let's go meet the prosecutors.
我能把咖啡带着吗
Can I bring my coffee?
1.75英寸
One and three quarters.
-不够好  -真是太操蛋了
- No good. - This is bullshit.
我被盘问了一天一夜  但是
I got grilled all day and all night and still...
我依然替你们带回来一只蟑螂
I brought back a bug for you.
一名检察官把它困在了文件和咖啡杯中间
A prosecutor trapped that between a file and a coffee cup
我把它放在胸罩里带回来了
and I carried it back in my bra.
你们就会满嘴狗屁谎话
You guys are full of shit.
根本没什么蟑螂生意
There's no roach business.
我不玩了  去你们的
I'm done. Fuck you.
我们听说你在利奇菲尔德监狱犯的事了
We heard of what you done back in Litchfield.
别以为那就能吓到我们
Don't think that scares us any.
没错
That's right.
你只杀过1个人
You... one.
我呢
Me?
杀过13个
Thirteen.
查普曼
Chapman...
你要上庭了
you're going to court.
别以为这样你就算脱身了  我们会等着的
Don't think this gets you off the hook. We'll be waitin'.
我不知道我是否能做到
I don't know if I can do it.
什么
What?
我的律师说库巴无论如何都会被关起来的
You know, my lawyer said Kubra's going away no matter what.
你没听见我之前跟你说的那些话吗
Did you not hear everything I said?
你之前不是还说不会出事的吗
When you told me that nothing bad was gonna happen?
你一直抓着这句话不放多久了
How long have you been holding onto that one?
我们的供述必须一致
We have got to go in united on this.
如果你说你认识他  我却说不认识  那就糟了
It'll be a red flag if you say you knew him and I say I don't.
他们会知道我在说谎
They'll know that I'm lying.
或许我们都该说实话
Maybe we should both just be honest.
这真是...
This is...
现在不是表现道德高尚的时候
This is not the time to take some moral high ground.
我似乎只有跟你在一起的时候
You know, I only seem to be faced with these extreme moral choices
才会面临这种极端的道德抉择
when I am with you.
很刺激  对吧
Exciting, right?
我也很希望可以将这一切重新来过
Look, I wish I could do this all over again,
但我做不到  明白吗
but I can't, okay?
现在这是我唯一可以保你周全的办法
This is the only way I can keep you safe now.
你必须按照我说的去做
You have to do what I'm telling you.
不然呢
Or what?
我们就完了吗
We're over?
不
No.
我想做你的狱中之妻
I wanna be your prison wife.
我很高兴你到这时候还能开玩笑
I'm glad you can make jokes.
艾丽克斯
Alex...
我得做一件正确的事了
I need to do the right thing for a change.
我必须这样
I have to.
老实说  你...
And truthfully, you...
你无论如何都没办法保我的安全
you can't keep me safe either way.
请伸出左手
Left hand, please.
举起右手
Raise your right.
你是否庄严地宣誓
Do you solemnly swear
你所说的全是事实真相
that you will tell the truth,
句句皆真  没有半点谎话
the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
-以求上帝庇佑  -我发誓
- so help you God? - I do.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了  我们可以开始了
All right, we can begin.
请向当庭说出你的全名
Will you state your full name for the court, please?
帕波・伊丽莎白・查普曼
Piper Elizabeth Chapman.
谢谢
Thank you.
查普曼小姐
Miss Chapman...
你目前正在联邦教改所
you are currently serving
为长达15个月的刑期服刑
a 15-month sentence in a federal penitentiary
所犯罪行与库巴・巴里克先生有关
for crimes associated with Mr. Kubra Balik,
是否属实
is that correct?
是的  属实
Yes, that's correct.
这些罪行是在什么时间犯下的呢
And when were these crimes committed?
不能说"这些"  我只犯了一桩罪行
Crime. It was just one crime.
是在2003年
In 2003.
好吧
Right.
你能否向我解释一下
And can you explain to me
你是如何跟巴里克先生的贩毒集团相识的呢
how you came to be associated with Mr. Balik's drug ring?
我当时的女友  艾丽克斯
My girlfriend at the time... Alex.
是艾丽克斯・沃斯小姐吗
Is that Miss Alex Vause?
是的
Yes.
你们现在还是情侣关系吗
Are you two still a couple?
不是
No.
但是2003年的时候
But in 2003...
你如何界定你们当时的关系
how would you describe the relationship?
我们当时在一起了
We were together.
她当时是  我此生的挚爱
She was... the love of my life.
是沃斯小姐介绍你认识巴里克先生的吗
And was it Miss Vause who introduced you to Mr. Balik?
我不记得了
I don't recall.
明白
I see.
是其他人介绍的吗
Someone else made the introduction?
我不记得了
I don't recall.
你是说你从没见过巴里克先生吗
Are you saying you never met Mr. Balik?
据我所知没有
Not that I can recall.
查普曼小姐  你的女友  沃斯小姐
Miss Chapman, your girlfriend... Miss Vause...
曾是巴里克先生手下赚钱最多的毒贩之一
was one of Mr. Balik's most profitable traffickers.
你知晓这一点吗
Were you aware of that?
我们当时并不怎么谈论她的业务
We didn't discuss her business much.
但你一定察觉到她是个成功人士
But you must've been aware of her success.
你和她一起环游各地  去了巴厘岛
You... you traveled together to Bali,
布鲁塞尔  巴黎  土耳其  希腊
Brussels, Paris, Turkey, Greece...
短短一年内就去了那么多地方
all in the span of one year.
我们确实经常旅行
We traveled a lot.
在此期间
And never in that time did
她就从来没介绍过你认识她的老板  库巴・巴里克吗
she introduce you to her boss, Kubra Balik?
据我所知是没有
Not that I can recall.
查普曼小姐
Miss Chapman...
你知道宣誓后作伪证的后果吧
you are aware of the consequences of lying under oath?
是的  当然了
Yes, of course.
你依然坚持刚刚的回答吗
And your responses remain the same?
我当时在艾丽克斯身边支持着她
I was there for Alex.
我的注意力只在她这个人身上
She was what I paid attention to...
她当时是我唯一在乎的人
who I paid attention to.
其他的一切都只是
Everything else was just...
不重要的背景
background.
抱歉我无法帮助你们更多
I'm sorry that I can't help you more.
检方已经完成了对该证人的询问
Prosecution has completed examination with this witness.
因为我不像我儿子那样是个蠢货
Since I'm not a half-wit like my son,
所以我也不必询问你为何那样做了
I don't have to bother asking why you did that.
我看如果出现...
I guess the possibility of...
加刑  或者面临新的指控
added time or... resentencing on new charges
对你来说也没什么大不了的
just isn't that big a deal for you.
很抱歉我让你失望了
I'm sorry I disappointed you.
让我失望
Disappointed me?
你又犯法了  而且是第二次
You broke the law... again.
我做出的这个决定并不期望你能理解
I made a decision that I don't expect you to understand.
反正没我的事儿了
Well, I'm done.
你活在一种危险的境地中  孩子
You live on this slippery slope, kid,
不知为何
and for some reason,
你还在做一些让自己陷入更危险境地的行为
you can't seem to stop doing rain dances.
祝你好运  亲爱的
Good luck, honey.
沃斯  你让我失望了  你是个让人失望的人
Vause, you let me down. You were a letdown.
当时是凌晨3点钟
It was 3:00 AM.
我觉得任何过了凌晨2点发生的事就...
I think that anything after 2:00, it's like...
不是故意要先走  只是累了而已
you're not bailing, you're just tired.
但你错过了活春宫秀
But you missed the live sex show.
以及火烈鸟
And the flamingos.
对哦  火烈鸟  没错
Oh, the flamingos! That's right!
还有火烈鸟呢
There were flamingos.
库巴得到的是两场表演的前排座位
Kubra had a front row seat to both.
一片粉色
So much pink.
我觉得我该去给我爸打个电话了
I think it's time for me to go call my dad.
跟比尔说我祝他生日快乐
Oh, tell Bill I said, "Happy birthday."
他不知道你的存在  记得吗
You don't exist, remember?
对哦  我是个隐形的女人
That's right. I'm the invisible woman.
或许我该换个职业  去当珠宝大盗
Maybe I should switch careers and become a jewel thief.
记得给我偷些宝贝
Steal me something good.
是的  一切都好
Yes, all good.
你呢  你过得怎么样
But what about you? How was your day?
挺好的  没什么大事
Oh, it was nice. Nothing crazy.
你妈和我一起出去吃晚餐了
Mom and I went out to dinner.
你呢  你还在巴塞罗那吗
How about you? You're still in Barcelona?
不  我们现在在巴黎
No, we're in Paris now.
真令人激动  宝贝
Oh, that's exciting, honey!
但千万别告诉我你是住在青年旅馆中的
But please tell me you're not staying in youth hostels.
-我可以给你汇钱的  -别担心
- I'm happy to wire you money. - Don't worry.
波丽在这边有亲戚  他们收留了我们
Polly has relatives here and they're letting us stay with them.
很美  很安全
It's... beautiful and it's safe.
Right 一词多义  右边/对  正确的
而且位于巴黎右岸
It's on the Right Bank.
总比位于"错岸"好吧
Better than the wrong bank.
真"好笑"  老爸
Ha-ha, Dad.
你很喜欢那儿吗  你和其他女孩相处得愉快吗
So you're loving it? You girls getting along?
你也知道波丽是个怎样的人
Well, I mean, you know how Polly is.
昨天她把我们的行程从早上到深夜都排满了
Yesterday she had us scheduled from morning until midnight.
你知道如果很晚了就得乘出租车的吧
You know if it's late, you need to take a taxi, right?
是的
Yes...
而且要永远沿着街道上灯光明亮的地方走
and always walk on the well-lit side of the street
看好钱包  别从巴士后面跳下去
and hold onto my wallet and don't jump out of the back of buses.
你教会了我一切  爸爸
You taught me everything, Dad.
真是我的乖女儿
You're a good girl.
谢谢  老爸
Thanks, Dad.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
生日快乐  老爸
Happy birthday, Daddy.
谢谢你  宝贝  谢谢你打电话过来
Thanks, baby. Thanks for calling.
艾丽克斯
Alex!
艾丽克斯  我按照你说的做了
Alex, I did what you said.
听着  帕波
Listen, Piper.
一切都发生得太快了
Everything just happened so fast.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我不得不说出真相
I had to tell the truth.
-我的律师说...  -你是在开玩笑吗
- My lawyer said that... - Are you kidding?
-帕波  你不明白  -你...
- Piper, you don't understand. - Are you...
你他妈是在开玩笑吗
Are you fucking kidding me?
你要去哪儿  你是要出狱了吗
Where are you going? Are you getting out?
真的对不起  对不起  帕波
I'm so sorry. I'm sorry, Piper.
-我会写信给你解释清楚的  -你要出狱了吗
- I'll write you. I need to explain. - You're getting out?
等等  什么
Wait, what?
你他妈的做了什么  艾丽克斯
What the fuck did you do, Alex?
你他妈的做了什么
What the fuck did you do?
操你妈的  艾丽克斯
Fuck you, Alex!
操你妈的
Fuck you!